

Vijay Rajan Machingauth

Engineering Manager Technical

338 W Rincon Ave, Campbell, California, US, CA 95008

(408)-797-4215

vijay.rajan@gmail.com

https://mvjay.github.io

English, Tamil, Malayalam, Hindi





BACKGROUND



Building & Leading high-velocity teams focused on delivering Complex Products, Experience managing cross-geo teams, Server SoC Power Management, Firmware Validation, Arch/Micro arch debug in Pre/Post Si Env, ARM and X86 architectures, CAD tools development for Microprocessors/Graphics, C, C++, Python, Perl & Ruby, Emulation bring up/debug/collateral development

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Engineering Manager Technical, IPG, Intel Corporation, Intel Corporation

Nov, 2015 - Present

Lead the Server Power Management Firmware Validation and the Intel Server Manageability IP Development Teams - Reponsible for delivery of Zero-Defect Power Management FW for all Intel Server Products & Intel Server Manageability IP. Also Lead the Power-Management IP Emulation Strategy

Senior Chief Engineer, Validation Architect, Samsung India Software Operations, Bangalore

Jul, 2014 - Sep, 2015 (3) 1 year 2 months

Senior Chief Engineer and Validation Architect responsible for Validation Strategy for Exynos Mobile SoCs. Simulation, Emulation, Multi-IP Validation & Multi-Processor Validation Strategies

Technical Lead, Post-Silicon Validation, Intel Technology India Pvt Ltd

May, 2012 - Jun, 2014 **②** 2 years 1 month

Lead a team focused on Xeon Power Management Post-Silicon Validation. Driving test content development, execution and debug. Responsibilities include content and execution planning, failure debug for internal and externally reported issues.

Lead Power Management Post-Si Validation of Jaketown, Ivytown and Broadwell Server

Technical Lead, Post-Silicon Debug and Debug tools, Intel Technology India Pvt Ltd

Jul, 2010 - Jun, 2014 3 years 11 months

Lead a team developing Post-Silicon Debug Tools. These tools are used for the Post-Si System Debug of Intel Multi-Core Xeon Microprocessors. Validation of Power-Management features and manual debug of failures.

